{
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "_____ used to generate electricity from wind",
      "answers": [ "windmill", "windgalss", "windfall", "windblast" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "_____ runs on coal",
      "answers": [ "car", "bus", "steam engine", "scooter" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Energy we get from sun is ______",
      "answers": [ "thermal", "hydel", "tidal", "solar" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "_____ is green gold",
      "answers": [ "Humans", "Plants", "Animals", "Soil" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "A gift of nature becomes resource when it satisfies human needs",
      "answers": [ "True", "False" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "We can create exhaustible resources",
      "answers": [ "True", "False" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Other name of petroleum is black gold",
      "answers": [ "True", "False" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Hydro electricity is generated from water",
      "answers": [ "True", "False" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "We must pollute air",
      "answers": [ "True", "False" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "(Write) Define fuel",
      "answers": [ "Material that burns to get energy", "material that satisfy our need", "both" ], "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "(Write) Define resource",
      "answers": [ "Material that burns to get energy", "material that satisfy our need", "both" ], "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "(Write) Two types of resources",
      "answers": [ "Natural(NR) and human made(HMR)", "land, air, water, soil are NR*",
                   "things made by humans like building, roads are HMR*", "all" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "(Write) uses of coal",
      "answers": [ "Used to cook, heat and generate electricity", "Used to run steam engine", "both" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "(Write) How can we conserve natural resources",
      "answers": [ "Plant more trees", "save electricity", "should not pollute air, water, soil",
                   "should not hunt wild animals", "all" ], "correct_answer": 5
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "(Write) Difference Exhaustible and In-exhaustible resource",
      "answers": [ "Gets exhausted after use", "called non-renewable resources", "Example- metal, coal, petroleum", "all" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "(Write) Difference In-exhaustible resource and Exhaustible",
      "answers": [ "Do not get exhausted after use", "called renewable resources", "Example- air, water, plant", "all" ], "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "(Write) New buildings have solar heaters and roof tops",
      "answers": [ "renewable and abundent", "to promote clean energy", "both" ], "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "(Write) Why plants are green gold",
      "answers": [ "plants are source of health and wealth", "give food, oxygen and other useful things", "both" ], "correct_answer": 3
    }
  ]
}

